<preferences>
	<primary_stats system="modified fuzion">
		<stat name="int">How generally bright you are. As a rule, this is more than sheer intelligence, but also includes cleverness, awareness, perception, and ability to learn.</stat>
		<stat name="ref">Your response time and coordination, as used in aiming, throwing, juggling. A stage magician, for example, would have a high Reflex Statistic. Most importantly, this is the Statistic that affects your ability to hit things.</stat>
		<stat name="tech">Your ability to manipulate tools or instruments. This is not the same as reflexes, inasmuch as this covers the knack of using tools. One character might have a high Technique, but might not be able to fence or juggle. On the other hand, another might have high Reflexes, but only a fair level of Technique.</stat>
		<stat name="dex">Your overall physical competence, as pertains to balancing, leaping, jumping, combat and other athletic activities. A gymnast would have a high Dexterity. Most importantly, this Statistic is used to avoid being hit.</stat>
		<stat name="pre">Your ability to impress and influence people through your character and charisma; how well you get along with others; how you interact in social situations.</stat>
		<stat name="str">Your muscle mass and how effective it is for exerting force. The higher your strength, the more you can lift, drag, etc., and the more powerful the blows from your fists and other body parts.</stat>
		<stat name="con">How healthy you are. How resistant to shock effects, poisons and disease. You can be a really big, tough, strong guy and still get floored by a head cold!</stat>
		<stat name="move">Your speed of movement; running, leaping, swimming, etc.</stat>
		<stat name="body">Your size, toughness, and ability to stay alive and conscious due to physical mass, sheer bloody-mindedness, structure or other qualities. How much damage you can take is derived from this characteristic.</stat>
		<stat name="will">Your determination and ability to face danger, stress or dehumanization. It also represents your courage and tenacity</stat>
	</primary_stats>
	<secondary_stats system="modified fuzion">
		<stat divider="2" first_source="int" multiplier="1" name="luck" second_source="ref" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="will" multiplier="10" name="hum" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="2" first_source="str" multiplier="1" name="rec" second_source="con" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="con" multiplier="2" name="end" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="move" multiplier="2" name="run" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="move" multiplier="3" name="sprint" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="move" multiplier="1" name="swim" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="move" multiplier="1" name="leap" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="body" multiplier="5" name="hits" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="body" multiplier="5" name="stun" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="con" multiplier="2" name="sd" second_source="none" />
		<stat divider="1" first_source="will" multiplier="3" name="res" second_source="none" />
	</secondary_stats>
	<skills system="modified fuzion">
		<skill>
			<name>Brawling / Hand To Hand</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Fighting</category>
			<description>The skill of fighting man to man with fist, feet and other parts of the body. Brawling is not a trained skill&#8212; it is learned on the Street by getting into a lot of fights. Unlike Martial Arts, there are no specialized attacks and no damage bonuses based on level of mastery.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Melee</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Fighting</category>
			<description>The ability to use knives, axes, clubs and other hand to hand weapons in combat. Note: when using non-ranged cyberweapons such as rippers, scratchers, slice n&#8217; dices, cyberbeasts, and battlegloves, you must use this skill. </description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Fencing</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Fighting</category>
			<description>The mastery of swords, rapiers and monoblades. A Fencing Skill of +3 allows you to be competent with a blade. A Skill of +5 makes you fairly skilled. A Fencing Skill of +6 might win you the National Fencing Competitions. A Skill of +8 will get you a reputation for being a true swordsman of duelist caliber. People like D&#8217;Artagnan or Miyamoto Musashi have Skills of +10. They are legendary masters of the blade: the mention of whom will cause all but the stupidest young bravo to run for cover</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Archery</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>The skill required to use bows, crossbows and other arrow-based ranged weapons. See Handgun for details.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Gunnery</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>The skill of using large vehicle weapons, ship-mounted weapons and artillery. At +2, you can fire the gun. At +5, you can compute ranges, azimuths and indirect fire. At +8, you can drop a shell right on top of a designated target.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Handgun</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>You must have this skill to effectively use handguns of any type, including cyberwear types. At +2, you can use a handgun effectively on a target range, though combat will still rattle you. At +5, you are as skilled as most military officers or policemen. At +7, you can do the sort of fancy shooting you see on TV, and have begun to get a reputation of being &#8220;good with a gun&#8221;. At +8, you are a recognized gunslinger with a &#8220;rep&#8221;. The very sound of your name makes some people back down in fear. At +10, you are a legendary gunslinger, feared by all except the stupid young punks who keep trying to &#8220;take&#8221; you in innumerable gunfight challenges.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Heavy Weapons</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>The required skill for using grenade launchers, autocannon, mortars, heavy machine guns, missiles and rocket launchers. A Level +5 skill would be equivalent to a general military &#8220;Heavy Weapons&#8221; training course, giving the user the ability to use any or all of these weapon types.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Rifle</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>You must have this skill to use rifles/shotguns effectively (see Handguns for limitations and modifiers).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Submachinegun</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Ranged Weapons</category>
			<description>You must have this skill to use any type of submachine gun effectively (see Handguns for limitations and modifiers).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Awarness / Notice</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>This is the equivalent of a &#8220;trained observer&#8221; skill, allowing characters to notice or be aware of clues, shadowers and other events. With an Awareness of +2 you will usually spot small pieces of paper with notes on them, doors left ajar, and obvious expressions of lying or dislike. An Awareness of +5 or better allows you to spot fairly well hidden clues, notice small changes in expression, and fairly sophisticated attempts to &#8220;shadow&#8221; you. With an Awareness of +8 or greater, you routinely perform the sorts of deductive reasoning seen in the average TV cop show (&#8220;The murderer was left handed because this knife has a specialized handle&#8221;). Sherlock Holmes has a +10 Awareness. Players without this skill may only use their Intelligence Stat.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Hide / Evade</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>The skill of losing pursuers, covering tracks and otherwise evading people on your trail. At +3, you can lose most boostergangers on the rampage. At +6, you can ditch cops and private eyes. At +8, you can ditch most Solos.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Lipreading</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>This skill enables the character to read someone&#8217;s lips in order to tell what is being said. The character must be able to see his target&#8217;s mouth clearly.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Shadow / Track</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>The skill of shadowing and following people. This skill is primarily used in urban or inhabited areas rather than in wilderness (where the skill of Survival incorporates tracking in the wilds).</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Surveillance</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>The ability to set up a static observation of a subject without being detected and to notice specific activities that may yield important information.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Driving</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>This skill allows you to pilot all ground vehicles like cars, trucks, tanks and hovercraft. This skill is not useable for piloting aircraft. A skill of +3 is equal to that of a very good non-professional driver. A skill of +6 allows you to drive with the skill of a moderately skilled race driver. An driver with a skill of +8 or greater will be nationally known as a racer, regularly win championship races, and possibly have access to the most advanced ground vehicles available (as long as he makes an endorsement).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Motorcycle</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The required skill to operate motorcycles, roadbikes and other two and three-wheeled vehicles.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Hvy. Machinery</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The required skill for using construction equipment, cranes and other large equipment. At +5, you are a proficient operator and could hold down a union job at the journeyman level.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Piloting</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>not found</category>
			<description>In general, this is the skill of controlling complex flying vehicles. These are broken into categories: Gyro and Rotorcraft, Fixed Wing Aircraft, Aeroliners and Vectored Thrust Aerodynes (AV-s). A Piloting Skill of +1 allows you to take off and land safely in good weather conditions. A Piloting Skill of +3 or more makes you a trained pilot, able to engage in most combat situations or bad weather. Pilots with a Skill of +6 or greater are veteran pilots, able to handle themselves in almost any situation, including aerobatic maneuvers. Pilots with a Skill of +9 or greater are so good, they have a rep as pilots, and are widely known among the piloting fraternity for having the &#8220;right stuff&#8221;.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pilot (Gyro)</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The ability to pilot all types of rotorwing aircraft, including gyros, copters and Jetfans.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pilot (Fixed Wing)</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The ability to pilot fixed wing jets and light aircraft. Jetfans may be flown with this skill, but only in the straight ahead (non-hover) mode.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pilot (Dirigible)</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The ability to pilot all lighter than air vehicles, including cargo aeroliners, blimps and powered balloons</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pilot (Vect. Thrust)</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The skill of piloting all types of vectored thrust vehicles, including fancars, hover rafts and AV-4, 6 and 7 vehicles.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Power Armor</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The skill of operating all types of powered armors, robotic suits and&#180;Ride armors.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Subjock</name>
			<stat>Ref</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The ability to pilot all types of submersible vehicles including minisubs and larger multicrew vehicles.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Link (mecha)</name>
			<stat>Will</stat>
			<category>Control</category>
			<description>The ability to interface with mecha: to control and operate mechapresence units. Note: Desnai mechajocks use Link instead of Power Armor skills.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Athletics</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>This skill is required for accurate throwing, climbing, and balancing. It combines the basic elements of any high school level sports program. At +3 and above, you are the equivalent of a real high school &#8220;jock&#8221;. At +5 and above, you can perform in college level competitions. At +8 and above, you are of Olympic or Professional caliber.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Dance</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>The specific skill needed to become a professional dancer. A trained dancer +4 or greater can successfully dance for payment in small clubs or dance troupes. Dancers +6 or greater will be considered to be of professional caliber, and regularly give performances and have fans. Dancers +9 or greater are of &#8220;star&#8221; caliber, have a large number of fans, and may be recognized on the street.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Dodge &amp; Escape</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>This skill is required to dodge attacks and escape grapples and holds. If an attack is made without your knowledge, you may not apply this skill to your Defense roll.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Endurance</name>
			<stat>Con</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>This is the ability to withstand pain or hardship, particularly over long periods of time, by knowing the best ways to conserve strength and energy. Endurance Skill checks would be made whenever a character must continue to be active after a long period without food, sleep or water.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Resistance</name>
			<stat>Will</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>Characters with this skill are especially toughened against interrogation, torture and mind control drugs. A successful use of this skill will automatically increase the difficulty of any interrogation attempt made by another party by one level. This skill may also be used in opposition to a Persuasion attempt.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Stealth</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description> The skill of hiding in shadows, moving silently, evading guards, etc. A Stealth Skill of +1 is about the level of a very sneaky 10 year old stealing cookies. At +3, you are able to get past most guards, or your parents if you&#8217;ve been grounded. At +6, you are good enough to slip smoothly from shadow to shadow and not make any noise. At +8, you are the equal of most Ninja warriors. At +10, you move as silently as a shadow, making the Ninja sound like elephants.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Strength Feat</name>
			<stat>not found</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>The user of this skill has practiced the art of bending bars, crushing objects, ripping phone books apart and other useful parlor tricks. At +2 you can crush cans, rip thin books in half, and bend thin rods. At +8, no phonebook is safe, you can bend thin rebar, and snap handcuffs. At +10, you can bend prison bars, rip up the Gutenberg Bible, and dent car fenders with one blow.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Swimming</name>
			<stat>Dex</stat>
			<category>Body</category>
			<description>This skill is required to know how to swim (see Athletics for details).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Animal Handling</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>This is the ability to train or direct animals through voice commands or hand signals: to train animals to perform tricks or tasks. At +2, you can get Fluffy to roll over. At +5, you can get Fluffy to lead you to the well where little Timmy has fallen in. At +9, Fluffy not only can bring you a beer, but (if he has hands) open the can and put it in a clean glass.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Bribery</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>A character with this skill knows when and where to bribe someone: how to approach them, and how much to offer. At +2, you can cut in line at the movies. At +5, you can get into exclusive clubs or fix a speeding ticket. At +8, you own members of Congress.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Interrogation</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of drawing information from a subject and forcing his secrets into the open. An Interrogation of +2 or better will allow you to infallibly find out if your boyfriend is lying to you. At +5, you are a professional level interrogator&#8212; equivalent to a skilled detective grilling a suspect. Mike Wallace of 60 Minutes has an Interrogation of +9, allowing him to make even the most powerful people squirm.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Intimidate</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of getting people to do what you want by force of personality or physical coercion. At +3, you can frighten almost any typical citizen, politician or low-level thug. At +6, you can intimidate Sylvester Stallone or any moderate &#8220;tough guy&#8221;. At +9, you could intimidate Gov. Schwartzenegger.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Oratory</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of public speaking. At +2, you can wing high school speeches. At +6, you can be paid to speak in public. At +10, you are capable of delivering a speech to rival Kennedy&#8217;s &#8220;Ich Bin Ein Berliner&#8221; or Lincoln&#8217;s Gettysburg Address.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Streetwise</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The knowledge of the &#8220;seamy&#8221; side of life&#8212;where to get illegal and contraband things, how to talk to the criminal element, and avoiding bad situations in bad neighborhoods. With a Streetwise of +2 or better, you can get &#8220;hot&#8221; items, score drugs, etc. A Streetwise of +5 would allow you to arrange a murder contract, know a few mobsters who might owe you favors, and be able to call on muscle when you need it. At +8 or better, you could become a major crimelord yourself and skip the middlemen.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Human Perception</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Awarness</category>
			<description>The skill of detecting lies, evasions, moods and other emotional clues from others. At +2, you can usually tell when you&#8217;re not getting the whole truth. At +6, you can detect subtle evasions and mood swings. At +8, you can not only detect subtle emotional clues, but can usually tell what the subject is hiding in a general way.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Interview</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of eliciting interesting anecdotes from an interview subject. This information will be of a more non-specific and personal nature rather than specific knowledge (distinguishing this skill from the skill of Interrogation, where the user is trying to extract exact information. Example: Barbara Walters interviews, Mike Wallace interrogates). At +3 or better, the subject will usually tell you only information relating to what he/she is well known for. At +6 or better, the subject will tell you anecdotes about the past, pontificate about favorite interests and philosophies, etc. At +9 or better, he/she tells you everything&#8212; including personal information about their illegitimate son, the time they stole a cookie at age 4, and the fact that no one ever loved them.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Leadership</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of leading and convincing people to follow you. A leader with a skill of +2 can manage a small office successfully and be respected for it. A leader with a skill of +4 or better can lead a small band of troops into battle and not get backshot. A leader with a skill of +7 or better can lead the entire Gamelon Empire into battle and look good doing it. James Kirk of Star Trek has a Leadership of +11, but you never will.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Seduction</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of forming and maintaining romantic relationships (this includes your abilities as a lover). This skill may be used to determine whether or not players can form relationships with other non-player characters and the intensity of these relationships. In certain cases, Referees may want to average this skill with a player&#8217;s Attractiveness to get a more realistic outcome.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Social Etiquette</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The ability to deal with social situations, like knowing the right fork to use or when not to tell the joke about the farmer&#8217;s daughter and the travelling cyberware salesman. A Social Skill of +2 or better will allow you to get by at any fine restaurant or social function. At +5, you can lunch with the President with aplomb. No social situation will faze you, no matter what. At +8 or above, you can lecture Emily Post on what&#8217;s proper.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Personal Grooming</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>This is the skill of knowing proper grooming, hair styling, etc., to maximize your physical attractiveness. Use of this skill allows players to increase their Attractiveness, and thus their chances of successful Relationships or Persuasions. A basically good looking person would be at +2. A fashion model might have a Personal Grooming of +5 or +6. At +8 or better, you could be a major fashion model, film star, or trendsetter. You are always &#8220;together&#8221;. And you know it.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Persuasion &amp; Fast Talk</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The ability to talk others into doing what you want. This may be used individually or on large groups. At +3, you can win most debates or convince your girlfriend that the blonde you were with was your sister. At +5, you are a smooth talker of professional caliber. Ronald Reagan has a Persuasion of +7. Hitler had a Persuasion of +9.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Wardrobe &amp; Style</name>
			<stat>Pre</stat>
			<category>Interaction</category>
			<description>The skill of knowing the right clothes to wear, when to wear them, and how to look cool even in a spacesuit. With a Wardrobe of +2 or better, you are good at choosing clothes off the rack. At +6, your friends ask you for wardrobe tips, and you never buy anything off the rack. At +8 or better, you are one of those rare people whose personal style influences major fashion trends.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Aero Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for repairing fixed wing aircraft, including Jetfans, jets, and light aircraft. With a Skill of +3, you can perform most routine maintenance tasks. With a Skill of +6, you can do engine teardowns and major structural repairs. With a Skill of +9 or better, you are capable of designing and building your own aircaft.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>AV Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for repairing all ducted fan aerodyne vehicles. At +3, you can perform routine maintenance. At +6, you can tear down engines and modify an AV. At +10, you can design your own AVs on common airframes.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Basic Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skills for building or repairing simple mechanical and electrical devices, such as car engines, television sets, etc. With a Basic Tech Skill of +3 or better, you can fix minor car problems, repair basic wiring, etc. A Basic Tech Skill of +6 or better can repair stereos and TVs, rebuild an engine, etc. A Basic Tech Skill of +9 or better can build a simple computer from scratch, put together a race car engine, and maintain any kind of industrial machinery. However, they do not know enough specialized knowledge to apply it to complex things such as aircraft (just like Mr. Goodwrench doesn&#8217;t know how to build and service an F-16).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Cryotank Operation</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for operating, repairing and maintaining life suspension and body chilling devices. A minimum skill of +4 is required to chill down a healthy person. A minimum skill of +6 for chilling a wounded person.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>CyberTech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for repairing and maintaining cyberwear. At level +2, you can keep your cyberwear tuned up and can replace its power batteries. At level +6, you can strip down most cyberwear and even make simple modifications. At level +8, you can strip down and rebuild any cyberware.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Demolitions</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>This skill allows the character to be knowledgeable in using explosives, as well as knowing the best types to use for which jobs, how to set timers and detonators, and how much explosive to use to accomplish a desired result.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Disguise</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of disguising your character to resemble someone else, whether real or fictitious. This skill incorporates elements of both makeup and acting, although it is not the same as the ability to actually be an actor.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Electronics</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for maintaining, repairing and modifying electronic instruments such as computers, personal electronics hardware, electronic security systems, cameras and monitors.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Elect. Security</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of installing or countering electronic eyes, electronic locks, bugs and tracers, security cameras, pressure plates, etc. At level +3, you can jimmy or install most apartment locks and security cams. At +6, you can override most corporate office locks and traps. At +9, you can enter most high security areas with impunity.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>First Aid</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>This skill allows user to bind wounds, stop bleeding, and stabilize a patient</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Forgery</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of copying and creating false documents and identifications. This skill may also be applied to the detection of same: if you can fake it, you can usually tell a fake as well.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Gyro Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of repairing and maintaining rotorwing aircraft such as helicopters and gyrocopters.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>3</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Jury Rig</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>This general repair skill allows the user to temporarily repair or alter anything for 1D6 turns per level of skill. This is not a permanent repair: after the elapsed time, the jury rig will break down.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Mecha Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of maintaining and repairing mecha, including Power Armors and Ride armors. At +1, you can change the fluids. At +5 you can change most standard parts equivalent to changing a spark plug. At +8 you can repair or change major operating systems equivalent to pulling a transmission .</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Medical Tech</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>not found</category>
			<description>This is the skill used to perform major surgery and medical repairs.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Paint or Draw</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of producing professional drawings. A Skill of +3 allows you to produce salable &#8220;modern&#8221; art. A Skill of +6 will produce artwork that is recognizable and extremely pleasant to the eye&#8212;as well as salable. An artist with a Skill of +8 or greater will be nationally known, have exhibits in galleries, and have other lesser artists studying his style in art school.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Photo &amp; Film</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of producing professional-caliber photographs or motion pictures. A Skill of +2 allows you to make decent home movies. A Skill of +4 creates work capable of winning amateur contests. A Skill of +6 will produce work of the level of the average Playboy cover or rock video. A photographer or cinematographer with a Skill of +8 or better will be nationally known and probably famous.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pharmaceuticals</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill of designing and manufacturing drugs and medicines. A minimum Chemistry skill of +4 is required. At +4, you can make aspirin. At +6, you can make hallucinogenics or antibiotics. At level +9 you can build designer drugs tailored to individual body chemistries.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pick Lock</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The skill required to pick locks and break into sealed containers and rooms. At +3, you can jimmy most simple locks. At +6 you can crack most safes. At +9 or better, you have a rep as a master cracksman, and are known to all the major players in the Cyberpunk world.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Pick Pocket</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for picking pockets without being noticed, as well as &#8220;shoplifting&#8221; small items. For ideas on levels of ability, see Pick Lock, above.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Weaponsmith</name>
			<stat>Tech</stat>
			<category>Technique</category>
			<description>The required skill for repairing and maintaining weapons of all types. At level +2, you can do repairs and field stripping. At level +6, you can repair all types of weapons and make simple modifications. At level +8, you can design your own weapons to order.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>2</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Inferface</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>not found</category>
			<description>not found</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Perform</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Performance</category>
			<description>The skill of trained acting, singing, etc. A trained performer of +4 or greater can successfully sing for payment at weddings or small clubs. Performers +6 or greater will be considered to be of professional caliber, and may have lucrative contracts and fans. Performers of +9 or greater are of &#8220;star&#8221; caliber, have a large number of fans, and may be recognized on the street.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Play Instrument</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Performance</category>
			<description>The skill of knowing how to play a musical instrument. You must take this skill separately for each type of instrument played. A Skill of +4 or higher will qualify your character to play professional &#8220;gigs&#8221;. A Skill of +8 and above will gain the musician some professional acclaim, possibly with recording contracts and command performances. At +10, you are widely acclaimed, have lots of Grammys, and regularly jam with a major musical act.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Ventriloquist</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Performance</category>
			<description>The skill of making your voice sound as if it is coming from another nearby location. At +5, they&#8217;ll never see your lips move.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Accounting</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The ability to balance books (or create false books), juggle numbers, create budgets and handle day to day business operations.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Anthropology</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The knowledge of human cultures, habits and customs. Unlike Streetwise (which covers only the cultures and customs of the Street), or Social (which covers only what you should do in a given situation), Anthropology covers general customs and background of a culture. For example, with Streetwise, you know what alleys to avoid and what gangs are dangerous. With Social, you know the proper forms of address for a high ranking Japanese zaibatsu head. With Anthropology, you know that the customs of a N&#8217;Tanga tribesman require that a young man kill a lion in order to be accepted as an adult male.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Biology</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>General knowledge of animals, plants, and other biological systems. At level +3, you know most types of common animals, plants. At +6, you have a general understanding of genetics, cellular biology, etc. At +10, you can perform most bio-lab procedures, including gene mapping and splicing.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Botany</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The general knowledge of plants and plant identification. At level +3, you know most common plants and can identify which ones are dangerous and why. At a +6, you can identify most important plants found worldwide and have a working knowledge of their uses. At +8, you have the equivalent of a doctorate in Botany and know all about rare poisons, exotic orchids and other useful plants.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Chemistry</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The required skill for mixing chemicals and creating various compounds. A level +2 Chemistry is equal to high school chemistry. A level +4 is equal to a trained pharmacist or college level chemist. A +8 is a trained laboratory chemist.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Coding</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The required skill to write programs and to re-program computer systems. This skill does not allow players to actually do repairs on a computer (this requires Electronics). With a Coding Skill of +1, you can write simple programs. A Skill of +3 means you know higher level languages and can write complex programs (including video games and mindcore programs). With a Skill +6 or better you&#8217;re considered a professional who can build all kinds of software. With a Skill of +9 or better, other coders speak your name with reverence (&#8220;You invented Q? Wow!&#8221;), young hackers set out to crack your systems, and any software you design instantly gets used in every business app or hack in the world.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Composition</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The required skill for writing songs, articles, or stories. A Composing Skill of +4 or greater gives your character the ability to produce salable work. A Skill of +8 or more produces work of such a high caliber that the creator may have a strong literary following and not a little critical acclaim.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Diagnose Illness</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The skill of clinically diagnosing symptoms and medical problems. A +3 is the equivalent of a high school nurse&#8212;you can recognize most common injuries and complaints. At +6, you would be equivalent to a trained intern: you can recognize many uncommon illnesses and know how to treat most common ones. A +9 is the equivalent of a skilled diagnostician: other physicians come to you to get a diagnosis.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Education &amp; Gen Know</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>This skill is the equivalent of a basic public school education, allowing you to know how to read, write, use basic math, and know enough history to get by. In effect, it is a &#8220;lore&#8221; or trivia skill. A level of +1 is a basic grade school education. A skill of +2 is equal to a high school equivalency. A Knowledge Skill of +3 is equal to a college education, +4 or higher is equal to a Masters or Doctorate. At +7, you are an extremely well-educated person, and are asked to play Trivial Pursuit a lot. At +9 and above, you are one of those people who knows a lot about every thing (and hopefully has the good sense to keep his mouth shut).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Expert</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>You may use this skill to be an expert on one specific subject, such as rare postage stamps, obscure weapons, a foreign language, etc. At +3, you are the local expert. At +6, you know enough to publish a few books on the subject. At +8 or better, your books are recognized as major texts on the subject, and you could do the talk-show circuit if you wanted to.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Gamble</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The skill of knowing how to make bets, figure odds, and play games of chance successfully. As any professional gambler knows, this is not a luck skill. At +2, you are the local card shark at the Saturday night poker game. At +6, you can make a living at the tables in Vegas and Monte Carlo. At +9 or better, you can take on James Bond at roulette and stand a good chance of breaking the bank.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Geology</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>A functional knowledge of rocks, minerals and geologic structures. At +3, you can identify most common rocks and minerals. At +6, you have the equivalent of a college degree in Geology and can identify minerals and geological structures with ease. At +8, you can teach geology in high school.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>History</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The knowledge of facts and figures of past events. In game play, this might be used to determine if a character is familiar with a particular clue related to a past event. At +2, you have the equivalent of a grade school history education. At +6, you would have the equivalent of a college grasp on the subject. At +8, you could teach history in high school. At +9, you may have written a few of the most oft-used texts on a particular historical personage or epoch.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Language</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The knowledge of a foreign tongue. At +2, you can &#8220;get by&#8221; with speaking the language. At +3, you can actually read a written form of it. At +6 and above, you are fairly fluent, although no native will be fooled by your ability. At +8 and above, you speak and read the language like a native. Each language known requires a separate Know Language Skill, however, one may use the knowledge of a particular Language with up to 1/2 (round down) proficiency with any language in the same linguistic family. Example: knowing Cantonese at +4 will give you the ability to understand and speak Mandarin at +2.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Library Search</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The skill of using databases, the DataPool, libraries and other compiled information sources to find facts. With a skill of +2 you can use most simple databases. With a skill of +6, you can easily access the Library Congress. At +9, you can comprehend almost any public database and find very obscure facts.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Mathematics</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The skill of understanding calculations and mathematical formulas. At +3, you have the ability to add, subtract, divide and multiply. At +4, you can do algebra and geometry. At +6, you can perform calculus. At +9 you can deduce your own mathematical formulas</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Market Trading</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The ability to speculate in tradegoods and commodities, to play stock markets, to engage in goods transactions and manipulate investments profitably. At +2, you know enough to invest in junk bonds and lose your shirt. At +6, your investments pay off 75% of the time. At +9, you are a major speculator, who routinely dabbles in international trade and can write learned articles on the subject of investment and speculation.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Physics</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The ability to calculate physical principles, such as gas pressures, mechanical energies, etc. This skill requires a basic Mathematics Skill of +4.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Teaching</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The skill of imparting knowledge to someone else (if you don&#8217;t think this is a skill, you ought to try it sometime). Players may not teach any skill unless they have a higher skill level than the student. The referee is the final arbiter of how long it takes to teach a skill. At a Teaching Skill of +3 or better, you can professionally teach students up to High School. At +6, you know enough to be a college professor (if you wanted). At +9 or greater, you are recognized by others in the field as good enough to guest lecture at MIT or CalTech: your texts on the subject are quoted as the major references, and you might have a TV show on the&#180;equivalent of the Discovey Channel.</description>
			<chippable>no</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Wilderness Survival</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>The required skill for knowing how to survive in the wilds. Knowledge includes how to set traps, forage for wood, track game, build shelters, make fires. The average Boy Scout has a Survival of +3. A Special Forces Green Beret has a Survival of +6 or above. Grizzly Adams, Mountain Man of the Wilderness, would have a +9 or +10 Survival Skill.</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
		<skill>
			<name>Zoology</name>
			<stat>Int</stat>
			<category>Education</category>
			<description>Knowledge of lifeforms, biological processes and their relation to the environment. At +2, you know most common animals. At +5, you know not only well known animals, but also about many exotics and endangered species. At +8, you are knowledgeable on almost all animals, know their habits well, and have a +1 advantage to any Wilderness Survival Skills (you know where to find the game).</description>
			<chippable>yes</chippable>
			<diff_modifier>1</diff_modifier>
		</skill>
	</skills>
	<complications system="modified fuzion">
		<complication>
			<name>Absend Minded</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You have strange lapses of memory. You often: Forget generally known facts (5). Forget friends, family (10). Forget your own identity (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Bipolar</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You are a classic manic/depressive, prone to fits of erratic, up moods punctuated with severe terrifying depressions. You are often: Moody (5). Liable to lie around and mope (10). Liable to run around frenetically risking life and limb or sink into a miserable stupor (15). Suicidal (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Delusions</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You believe things that are not real. You may hear voices, think aliens are after you, or that you are God. You will: Risk ostracism, embarrassment (5). Risk hospitalization, bodily harm or financial/social ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15) .</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Masochist</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You hate yourself, and will go out of your way to injure yourself. To do this, you may: Seek verbal abuse (5). Seek minor physical abuse (10), Seek major physical abuse (15). Seek life threatening abuse (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Paranoia</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>(just because you think they&#8217;re after you...). You think you have enemies, everywhere. Sometimes you are focussed on one foe, other times, there may be legions. You react to your paranoia by: Incoherently ranting (5). Compulsively working on defenses against Them (10). Risking incarceration, bodily harm, social or financial ruin to stop Them (15). Risking life &amp; limb (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Phobia</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You have a phobia: and unreasoning fear of some common thing, such as dogs, heights, sounds or color. When faced with your phobia, you feel: Discomfort (5). Paralyzing Fear (10). Berserk Terror (15). Catatonic (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Split Personality</name>
			<category>Psychological Complications</category>
			<description>You&#8217;re two, two, TWO people in one! [GM controls this personality, has character sheet for it, etc.]. Your other self: Likes you (5). Is neutral to you (10). Hostile to you (15). Dangerous to you in actions (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Airhead</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>Oh Wow! You&#8217;re just naturally spacy. In general, you: Misplace minor, trivial things (5). Misplace or forget to do important things (10). Misplace or forget to deal with dangerous things (15). Dangerously oblivious to everything: the GM never asks you to make a perception roll unless you request it (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Bad Tempered</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You&#8217;re just irritable, all the time. When your temper flares: You&#8217;ll risk embarrassment, or financial loss (5). You&#8217;ll risk incarceration, bodily harm or financial/social ruin (10). You&#8217;ll risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Coward</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You lack nerve, especially in combat. When faced with danger: You tremble at anything you imagine as danger (5). You freeze up and can&#8217;t react (10). You try to run as far away as possible (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Obsessed</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You just can&#8217;t get that special (to you) person or thing out of your mind. You: Talk about it all the time and will risk embarrassment, or financial loss over it (5). You&#8217;ll risk incarceration, bodily harm or financial/social ruin over it (10). You&#8217;ll risk life &amp; limb over it (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Shy</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You hate dealing with others. You: Refuse to speak to new people (5). Avoid all interactions with new people (10). Will physically remove self from situations involving new people (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Stubborn</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You just hate to give in&#8212;to anyone. To prove you&#8217;re right: You&#8217;ll risk embarrassment, or financial loss (5). You&#8217;ll risk incarceration, bodily harm or financial/social ruin (10). You&#8217;ll risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Berserker</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>You can&#8217;t control your fighting rage&#8212; you rabidly: Attack whatever set you off (5). Attack anyone within range except friends (10). Attack anyone in range (15). Attack anyone in range and won&#8217;t stop until subdued forcibly or exhausted/stunned (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Unlucky</name>
			<category>Personality Traits</category>
			<description>Things never go your way: you have constant disasters. Travel and adventure only hold for you: Inconvenient misfortunes (5). Costly or dangerous misfortunes (10). Very costly or dangerous misfortunes (15). Deadly, life threatening dangers (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Missing limb</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>Ouch! That hurt! You&#8217;re missing: 1 or more fingers (5). A hand (10 each). An arm (15 each).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Reduced Hearing</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>You are hard of hearing. Generally, to make a hearing based Perception check, you will need: To beat a Target Number 4 points higher than everyone else's (5). A Hearing aid just to hear at all (10). New ears: you&#8217;re totally deaf (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Reduced Mobility</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>You are unable to get around normally. Your Movement: Is reduced by quarter (5). Is reduced by half (10). Is reduced to dragging by arms at a MOVE of 1 (15). Nonexistent: you&#8217;re a total quadriplegic: unable to move below the neck (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Reduced Sight</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>Your eyesight is impaired in some way. You are: Color blind (5). Need glasses (10). Are nearly blind or one-eyed (15). Are totally blind (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Uncontrollable Change</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>You are prone to uncontrollable changes: these may be physical or mental (depending on what you negotiate with the GM). What sets off the change is: Uncommon (5). Common (10). Very Common (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Vocal Impairment</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>Your voice is somehow damaged. When you speak, you can: Only whisper, stammer or stutter (5). Only make sounds, but cannot speak (10). Cannot make a sound (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Vulnerability</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>You&#8217;re susceptible to a certain situation or substance and take extra damage when exposed to it (such as you drown faster than other people.) The substance or situation is: Uncommon (5). Common (10). Very Common (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Susceptibility</name>
			<category>Physiological Limitations</category>
			<description>You are harmed or take damage from a certain situation or substance that is harmless to other people (like water. dus, or that glowing green alien rock over there) The substance or situation is: Uncommon (5). Common (10). Very Common (15)</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Public Figure</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>You are a figure in the media limelight: you can&#8217;t make a move without getting attention: You are newsworthy and your activities rate an article if a reporter is nearby (5). You frequently make headlines and people always notice your actions on the street (10). Your every action makes news and you have reporters following you everywhere (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Bad Rep</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>People &#8220;know&#8221; about you. At least, everyone&#8217;s heard a story or two, even if untrue. When you are mentioned or seen, you are: Frequently recognized (5). Always recognized (10).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Secret Identity</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>You are trying to hide your activities under a secret identity or other smoke screen. You currently are: Living a normal life, unnoticed by anyone (5). Are bothered by a single person trying to uncover your real identity (10). Everyone&#8217;s trying to uncover your real identity (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Poverty</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>Money is hard to come by for you, harder than for most. You are, financially-wise: Poor, with just enough for a bed and a few meager meals (5). Dead Broke and probably on the street with barely enough to eat (10). In debt, with others actively seeking to collect what little you have (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Personal Habits</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>People just can&#8217;t stand you. Maybe it&#8217;s the bad breath or the nose picking, but they find you: Annoying (5). Disgusting (10). Horrible (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Oppressed</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>You are part of an oppressed or otherwise downtrodden group. In your society, you are: Snubbed: others ignore or refuse to deal with you (5). Oppressed: there are laws controlling where you live, work or can travel (10). Outcast: you&#8217;re a total non-person (15). Enslaved: you&#8217;re treated as property and can be sold or mistreated at will (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Distinctive</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>You stand out and are noticed in any crowd, with features that are: Easily concealed (5). Concealable with Disguise or Performance skills (10). Not concealable (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Outsider</name>
			<category>Social Complications</category>
			<description>You&#8217;re not a local, and stand out like a sore thumb, attracting attention both unwelcome and possibly dangerous. You are obviously: From distant place (5). From very distant place (10). Never before seen in these parts (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Code of Honor</name>
			<category>Responsibilities</category>
			<description>These are the personal rules you will not break, no matter what. A Code of Honor might be a code against killing, never attacking from behind, or never suffering an insult without an answer in blood. To keep your Code, you will: Risk expulsion or embarrassment (5). Risk bodily harm or financial ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Sense of Duty</name>
			<category>Responsibilities</category>
			<description>You always do the Right Thing, and follow a higher Moral Code towards those you feel responsible for. You will do this: For your friends (5). For a special group/organization (10). For all Humanity (15). For all Life Itself (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Vow</name>
			<category>Responsibilities</category>
			<description>This is a promise you must keep, no matter what. It could be to protect someone, follow an ideal, or just get that stupid Ring into that distant volcano. To fulfill this promise, you&#8217;ll: Risk Expulsion or embarrassment (5). Risk bodily harm or financial ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Dependents</name>
			<category>Responsibilities</category>
			<description>These are those who need your protection and help. They could include children, family, or friends. Generally, they are: Equal to you in abilities (5). Challenged, or otherwise weaker than you (10). Have special problems, requirements or dangers associated with them (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Addiction</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>(aka Dependence). You must have a particular substance or situation or you will suffer severe mental or physical duress. The substance/situation you need is: Common (5). Uncommon (10). Rare (15). Very Rare (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Honesty</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You always tell the truth, even if it hurts. To be honest, you&#8217;ll even: Risk expulsion, embarrassment, or financial loss (5). Risk bodily harm or financial/social ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Impulsiveness</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You just can&#8217;t help yourself: you always jump into things without thinking. To follow a whim, you&#8217;ll: Risk expulsion or embarrassment (5). Risk bodily harm, social or financial ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Intolerance</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You&#8217;re bigoted and intolerant of those who are different from you. When you encounter them, you are: Civil but distant (5). Rude and verbally abusive (10). Violently abusive (15). Abusive even at risk of life and limb (20).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Jealousy</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You are jealous in the extreme. Towards the one you &#8220;love&#8221;, you are: Obsessed and watchful (5). Confrontative and accusatory (10). Physically violent ((15).</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Kleptomania</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You steal things continuously. You can&#8217;t help it: you&#8217;ll even: Risk arrest or embarrassment (5). Risk bodily harm or financial/social ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15)</description>
		</complication>
		<complication>
			<name>Lecherous</name>
			<category>Compulsive Behaviors</category>
			<description>You can&#8217;t resist grabbing or pawing someone you find attractive, or at least making lewd comments. You&#8217;ll even: Risk expulsion, embarrassment, or financial loss (5). Risk bodily harm or financial or social ruin (10). Risk life &amp; limb (15)</description>
		</complication>
	</complications>
	<talents system="modified fuzion">
		<talent>
			<name>Acute Senses</name>
			<description>One of your five senses (sight, sound, smell, touch, taste) is extremely acute. If the sense is touch, you can read print with your fingertips, feel tumblers moving in a lock, and determine subtle differences in materials by feel. If the sense is smell, you can instantly detect people or substances by scent alone and can track them like a bloodhound. If the sense is sight, you automatically gain a +1 bonus in all sight related Awareness checks, and treat all ranged attack modifiers as being 2 points less than normal. If the sense is taste, you can perceive subtle additions to food and detect harmful substances with the barest taste.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Ambidexterity</name>
			<description>You can use tools and weapons with either hand at no penalty (normally -3 for using off-hand).</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Animal Empathy</name>
			<description>Animals like you; they will never harm or attack you unless severely provoked. You always seem to attract whatever animals are common to the area, and they will immediately gravitate to your side, although they may not necessarily do what you ask them to.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Beatiful / Handsome</name>
			<description>You are extremely good looking; people will automatically stop and stare at you when you pass, and you are generally surrounded by admirers. In addition, you automatically have a +1 bonus to your Persuasion, Performance, and Wardrobe/Style skills for each level taken.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Blind Reaction</name>
			<description>You can counterattack (in hand-to-hand only) with no negative modifiers for darkness or being obscured (-4), even if you can't see or hear your opponent.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Charismatic Leadership</name>
			<description>This Talent allows the user to sway crowds equal to his level times 200. This ability (added to your Pre stat) allows the character to control, incite and charm large number of people through his or her performance skills. When under the character's control, this group can easily be persuaded to act on his suggestions; for example, with a high Charismatic Leadership, a character could convince a concert crowd to riot in the streets or attack a heavily fortified police line. Charismatic Leadership will only work with groups of ten or more people as it is primarily a mob leadership ability. The higher your Charismatic Leadership, the larger a crowd you can control and the more direct and complex the instructions you can get them to follow. For example, a Level +3 Leadership could incite a nightclub crowd to get rowdy. A Level +5 or +6 could provoke a concert crowd of thousands to trash a neighborhood, if the area wasn&#8217;t too far from the hall. At Level +9, and higher, you have the same sort of mesmeric ability as an Adolph Hitler&#8212;you can raise armies, start movements, and destroy nations.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Combat Sense</name>
			<description>Combat Sense allows the user to perceive danger, notice traps, and have an almost unearthly ability to avoid harm. Your Combat Sense gives you a bonus on both your Awareness skill and your Initiative equal to your level in the Combat Sense skill. Your reflexes are keyed for danger; you automatically react faster to danger than anyone else; for every level taken (up to 5) you may add +1 to your Initiative rolls (in combat only). This ability is based on constant training and professionalism.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Common Sense</name>
			<description>You always look before you leap; the Ref must give you warning whenever you&#8217;re about to do something particularly foolish, even if there are no perceptible clues present. He doesn&#8217;t have to specify the danger, just that "this might not be a smart idea..."</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Direction Sense</name>
			<description>You are never lost, always know where North is and can orient yourself easily without any external cues.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Double Jointed</name>
			<description>You can bend your limbs and joints in impossible ways. You can fit into any space equal to half your height and width and it is impossible to tie you up or entangle you with a single rope; you can only be restrained using restraints like cuffs, shackles, or nets.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Eidetic Memory</name>
			<description>You never forget anything you have read, seen, heard, smelled, or touched.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>High Pain Threshold</name>
			<description>You are especially resistant to pain and shock. When wounded, you will reduce the amount of STUN taken by 2 points each time and the effects of impairing wounds (when used) by -2.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Immunity</name>
			<description>You are immune to the effects of one specific poison or disease group (must specify).</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Intuition</name>
			<description>You have an uncanny feel for hunches; the Ref will give you a chance to make a Awareness roll whenever he thinks you might get a hunch, even if there are no perceptible clues present.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Lightning Calculator</name>
			<description>You can automatically do complex mathematical operations in your head without using any aids.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Light sleeper</name>
			<description>You wake instantly from even the lightest touch or smallest sound (no Awareness check required).</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Longevity</name>
			<description>You are extremely long lived, but do not show any appreciable signs of aging. No matter how old you are, you always look and feel as a person half your age.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Night Vision</name>
			<description>You can see in all but absolute darkness.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Perfect Pitch</name>
			<description>You always know if something&#8217;s in tune, and automatically gain a +3 bonus in any musically related task (singing, playing instruments, etc).</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Rapid Healing</name>
			<description>You heal extremely fast, recovering an extra 3 Hits per day in addition to your normal healing rate.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Schtick</name>
			<description>A schtick is a special habit or personal affectation that has little or no actual effect on skills or combat abilities. Examples might be: always having a wind wafting your hair or cape dramatically, always having dramatic lighting striking your face, being able to toss your hat on a hook when you walk in; always having a cigar hidden somewhere on your person, etc. Schticks must be okayed by the Ref and should never have an important combat or skill application&#8212;always shooting the gun out of the bad guy&#8217;s hand would be a very dangerous schtick to allow.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Simulate Death</name>
			<description>You can lower your heart rate and breathing to such a low level that it is a Very Hard Difficulty to tell whether you are dead or not.</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Speed Reeder</name>
			<description>You can read one page of any normal text that you are familiar with in three seconds (you can read a 200 page book in 10 minutes).</description>
		</talent>
		<talent>
			<name>Time Sense</name>
			<description>You always know what time it is, always know how much time has elapsed between the present and the last time you checked.</description>
		</talent>
	</talents>
	<perks system="modified fuzion">
		<perk>
			<name>Membership</name>
			<description>[1 per level] You can call upon the resources of an organization, person, government, Altcult or group&#8212;but you also have responsibilities. The level of Membership represents your character&#8217;s status in the organization, not the influence of the group (that&#8217;s what the multipliers above are for). For example: A Membership of 1 at in the FBI would make you a janitor, but at 10 you&#8217;re the Director&#8217;s right-hand man. A version of this is Authority, in which the character is an agent of the law and has the power to arrest, detain and use deadly force.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Contact</name>
			<description>[1 per level] You know someone who can (and generally will) help you through money, power or sheer skill, and this help is usually &#8220;off the record.&#8221; A mercenary who&#8217;ll occasionally back you up in a fight costs 3, a local Yakuza Boss costs 6, the head of NC SWAT costs 9. Remember that the level of the contact is based on several factors: a student&#8217;s not much, but a student who&#8217;s willing to die for you&#8230;</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Favor</name>
			<description>[0.5 per level] A one shot Contact; you can make use of this contact only once, but they MUST do what you ask (as long as its appropriate). Note that it&#8217;s often useful to have favors from a lot of people in different areas rather than one contact who does everything.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Renown</name>
			<description>[1 per level] Your reputation, usually in a favorable light. People go out of their way to curry favor with you, or to at least avoid getting on your bad side. At 3, most local people know you; at 6 you&#8217;re nationally known; at 9 you&#8217;re an international figure.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Wealth</name>
			<description>[5 per level] In Cyberpunk, characters are assumed to be lower class (heck, you&#8217;re dirt poor), but wealth boosts your lifestyle. Spending 1 CP places you comfortably in the middle class, capable of buying common things and living in a decent place. Level 2 is upper middle class; you can buy most everyday things and live in a very nice place. At levels 3-4, you are well to do and have more than enough money to support yourself; you need work only occasionally can afford costly hobbies, and have an expensive home. At 6 you&#8217;re rich; you don&#8217;t have to work at all, can afford large purchases like cars or vacations, and live in a very expensive home. At 8, you&#8217;re a millionaire, can live anywhere and buy almost anything you want. The Ref might even let you exceed Wealth 10, making you a billionaire!</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Authority</name>
			<description>[ 1 per level] The ability to intimidate or control others through your position as a lawman. This attribute represents the&#180;character&#8217;s ability to call on the forces of Law and Order to get what he wants. Cops can use Authority to question suspects, arrest wrongdoers, and defend innocents. Backed by the power of Authority, a character can arrest, detain, confiscate and enter nearly anywhere, as long as he has the proper arrest or search warrants to back his play. However, Authority is only as good as the guy holding the badge&#8212;if the character appears uncertain of his Authority, there&#8217;s a good chance he&#8217;ll get nailed by the people he&#8217;s trying to confront. The higher your Authority, the more able you are to face down people, particularly high level corporates and government officials. Authority is applied to your Pre stat.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Credibility</name>
			<description>[1 per level] This is the ability to be believed: by your viewers, by the police, by important and powerful people. This is critical to getting your side of the story heard and acted upon, as well as convincing people to tell you things, give you information, or get you into where the story is really happening. The higher your Credibility, the more people you can convince, and the easier it is to convince high level authorities of the truth of your information. With a level +3 Credibility, you can convince most people of minor scandals. With a level +5 or +6, you can convince local officials of military atrocities, undercover dealings and other front page stuff. At level +9, you can successfully expose a scandal of Watergate proportions, or convince the President of the EuroMarket Finance Board that aliens are secretly influencing world leaders. Credibility applies to your INT stat.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Family</name>
			<description>[1 per level] This is the ability to call upon the resources and help of any of the members of a large, extended family (like an Altcult). This can be in the form of weapons, cash, information, or a small army of relatives. The threat of a family&#8217;s vengeance may in itself stop harm to the character. The higher your Family Perk, the more important you are to the family and the more help you can call upon. With a Family of +2, you might be able to get several members of the Family to help you wreck a town, for example. With a status of +7 or +8, you are able to influence major group decisions and lead troops. At +10, you may be the head of your Family.</description>
		</perk>
		<perk>
			<name>Streetdeal</name>
			<description>[1 per level] This is the ability to deal with the underground information network. With Streetdeal, a character can uncover rumors and information, locate missing persons or things, put gossip out on the Street, pick up clues and score big deals. The higher your Streetdeal, the more information you can gather about things happening around you, the more informants you have, and the more secretive the information you can dig up. A level +3 Streetdeal can get you contacts for weapons, tools, or minor illegal operations. At level +5, you can penetrate the secrets of all but the most powerful crime families. At level +9, you are the equivalent of a Mafia crimelord yourself, privy to every secret that&#8217;s on the Street. Apply Streetdeal to your Pre stat.</description>
		</perk>
	</perks>
	<tables system="modified fuzion">
		<table name="affections">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Tattoos</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Shades/Glasses</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Scaring/Branding</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Spiked Gloves</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Earrings</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Long Fingernails</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Heels</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Weird Lenses</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Fingerless Gloves</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Jewellery</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Piercing</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Hats/Caps</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Gloves/Boots</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Make-up/Face Paint</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Skin Tints</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Goggles &amp; Gear</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Androgyne Make-up</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Bandanna/Hairband</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Waist Pouch</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="clothes">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Leathers</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Denim/Jeans</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Corporate Suits</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Coveralls/Jumpsuits</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Short, Open</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">High Fashion</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Cammos</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Normal Clothes</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Lingerie/Nude</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Tribal Dress</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Generic</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Ethnic/Historical</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Kung-Fu Pj's</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Utilitarian</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Leisure Wear</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Urban Flash/Yakuza</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Big Suits</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Bag Lady Chic</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Paramilitary</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="disorders">
			<choice from="1" to="1">None</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Homicidal</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Suicidal</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Schizophrenic</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Sociopath</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Delusions</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Technophobe</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Addict</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Agoraphobic</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Hallucinations</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Megalomania</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Compulsive Liar</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Pyromaniac</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Martyr</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Multiple Personalities</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Sado-masochist</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="exmodes">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Antisocial/Solitary</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Aloof/Spacey</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Sober/Secretive</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Shy/Quiet</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Intellectual/Detached</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Intuitive/Spiritual</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Diplomatic/Courteous</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Silly/Manic</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Friendly/Helpful</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Arrogant/Rude</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Forceful/Aggressive</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Suspicious/Nervous</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Guilty/Depressive</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Antagonistic/Hostile</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Cheerful/Fluff-headed</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Angry/Quick-Tempered</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Assured/Stylish</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="hair">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Mohawk</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Long &amp; Ratty</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Spiked</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Wild &amp; All Over</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Bald/Shaved</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Striped</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Tinted/Dyed</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Short, Neat</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Short, Curly</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Long, Straight</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Dreads</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Natural, Long</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Braids, Wraps</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Shoulder Length</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Crew/Fade Cut</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Slicked Back</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Perm/Big Hair</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Tied</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Box Fade</choice>
			<choice from="20" to="20">Tech Cut</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="inmodes">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Optimist</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Pessimist</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Hedonist</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Suspicious</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Egotist</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Mischievous</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Curious</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Moody</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Trusting</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Opinionated</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Treacherous</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Malevolent</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Forgiving</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Unforgiving</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Vengeful</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Jealous</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Lazy</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Driven</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Cowardly</choice>
			<choice from="20" to="20">Brave</choice>
			<choice from="21" to="21">Honest</choice>
			<choice from="22" to="22">Ponderous</choice>
			<choice from="23" to="23">Scheming</choice>
			<choice from="24" to="24">Skeptic</choice>
			<choice from="25" to="25">Manipulative</choice>
			<choice from="26" to="26">Greedy</choice>
			<choice from="27" to="27">Pious</choice>
			<choice from="28" to="28">Lustful</choice>
			<choice from="29" to="29">Perverse</choice>
			<choice from="30" to="30">Nihilistic</choice>
			<choice from="31" to="31">Honorable</choice>
			<choice from="32" to="32">Compassionate</choice>
			<choice from="33" to="33">Disorder</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="phobias">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Ablutophobia (washing or bathing)</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Acousticophobia (noise)</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Acrophobia (heights)</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Agoraphobia (open spaces, leaving safe place)</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Amathophobia (dust)</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Androphobia (men)</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Anthropophobia (people or society)</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Arachnophobia (spiders)</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Astraphobia (thunder and lightning)</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Asymmetriphobia (asymmetrical things)</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Ataxophobia (disorder or untidiness)</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Autophobia (being alone, oneself)</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Aviophobia (flying)</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Batrachophobia (amphibians)</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Bibliophobia (books)</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Botanophobia (plants)</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Catoptrophobia (mirrors)</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Chaetophobia (hair)</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Cheimaphobia (cold)</choice>
			<choice from="20" to="20">Claustrophobia (confined spaces)</choice>
			<choice from="21" to="21">Coulrophobia (clowns)</choice>
			<choice from="22" to="22">Cyberphobia (computers, cybernetics)</choice>
			<choice from="23" to="23">Cynophobia (dogs or rabies)</choice>
			<choice from="24" to="24">Cypridophobia (prostitutes or venereal disease)</choice>
			<choice from="25" to="25">Dishabiliophobia (undressing in front of someone)</choice>
			<choice from="26" to="26">Doraphobia (fur or skins of animals)</choice>
			<choice from="27" to="27">Ecclesiophobia (church)</choice>
			<choice from="28" to="28">Electrophobia (electricity)</choice>
			<choice from="29" to="29">Entomophobia (insects)</choice>
			<choice from="30" to="30">Epistemophobia (knowledge)</choice>
			<choice from="31" to="31">Felinophobia (cats)</choice>
			<choice from="32" to="32">Genophobia (sex)</choice>
			<choice from="33" to="33">Gerontophobia (old people or of growing old)</choice>
			<choice from="34" to="34">Gymnophobia (nudity)</choice>
			<choice from="35" to="35">Gynophobia (women)</choice>
			<choice from="36" to="36">Haematophobia (blood)</choice>
			<choice from="37" to="37">Haptophobia (being touched)</choice>
			<choice from="38" to="38">Hedonophobia (feeling pleasure)</choice>
			<choice from="39" to="39">Heliophobia (the sun)</choice>
			<choice from="40" to="40">Hellenologophobia (complex terminology)</choice>
			<choice from="41" to="41">Herpetophobia (reptiles or creepy, crawly things)</choice>
			<choice from="42" to="42">Hippopotomonstrosesquippedaliophobia (long words)</choice>
			<choice from="43" to="43">Hobophobia (bums or beggars)</choice>
			<choice from="44" to="44">Hodophobia (travel)</choice>
			<choice from="45" to="45">Hoplophobia (firearms)</choice>
			<choice from="46" to="46">Hypengyophobia (responsibility)</choice>
			<choice from="47" to="47">Hydrophobia (water)</choice>
			<choice from="48" to="48">Kakarrophiaphobia (failure)</choice>
			<choice from="49" to="49">Kinetophobia (movement or motion)</choice>
			<choice from="50" to="50">Laliophobia (speaking)</choice>
			<choice from="51" to="51">Lunaphobia (the moon)</choice>
			<choice from="52" to="52">Martiophobia (weapons)</choice>
			<choice from="53" to="53">Mechanophobia (machines)</choice>
			<choice from="54" to="54">Melanophobia (the colour black)</choice>
			<choice from="55" to="55">Melophobia (music)</choice>
			<choice from="56" to="56">Methyphobia (alcohol)</choice>
			<choice from="57" to="57">Microphobia (small things)</choice>
			<choice from="58" to="58">Motorphobia (automobiles)</choice>
			<choice from="59" to="59">Musophobia (mice, rodents)</choice>
			<choice from="60" to="60">Mysophobia (dirt)</choice>
			<choice from="61" to="61">Necrophobia (death or dead things)</choice>
			<choice from="62" to="62">Neophobia (new ideas, ways)</choice>
			<choice from="63" to="63">Nosocomephobia (hospitals)</choice>
			<choice from="64" to="64">Nyctophobia (the dark)</choice>
			<choice from="65" to="65">Ochlophobia (crowds or mobs)</choice>
			<choice from="66" to="66">Octophobia (the figure 8)</choice>
			<choice from="67" to="67">Ombrophobia (rain or of being rained on)</choice>
			<choice from="68" to="68">Onomatophobia (hearing a certain word)</choice>
			<choice from="69" to="69">Ophidiophobia (snakes)</choice>
			<choice from="70" to="70">Ornithophobia (birds)</choice>
			<choice from="71" to="71">Ostraconophobia (shellfish)</choice>
			<choice from="72" to="72">Paraskavedekatriaphobia (friday the 13th)</choice>
			<choice from="73" to="73">Pathophobia (disease)</choice>
			<choice from="74" to="74">Patriphobia (authority)</choice>
			<choice from="75" to="75">Pediophobia (dolls)</choice>
			<choice from="76" to="76">Pedophobia (children)</choice>
			<choice from="77" to="77">Peladophobia (bald people)</choice>
			<choice from="78" to="78">Pharmocophobia (drugs)</choice>
			<choice from="79" to="79">Piscophobia (fish)</choice>
			<choice from="80" to="80">Pogonophobia (beards)</choice>
			<choice from="81" to="81">Pyrophobia (fire)</choice>
			<choice from="82" to="82">Radiophobia (radiation, x-rays)</choice>
			<choice from="83" to="83">Ranidaphobia (frogs)</choice>
			<choice from="84" to="84">Rupaphobia (filth)</choice>
			<choice from="85" to="85">Sciophobia (shadows)</choice>
			<choice from="86" to="86">Scoleciphobia (worms)</choice>
			<choice from="87" to="87">Staurophobia (crosses or the crucifix)</choice>
			<choice from="88" to="88">Symmetrophobia (symmetry)</choice>
			<choice from="89" to="89">Tachophobia (speed)</choice>
			<choice from="90" to="90">Technophobia (technology)</choice>
			<choice from="91" to="91">Telephonophobia (telephones)</choice>
			<choice from="92" to="92">Textophobia (certain fabrics)</choice>
			<choice from="93" to="93">Thermophobia (heat)</choice>
			<choice from="94" to="94">Topophobia (certain places/situations, stage fright)</choice>
			<choice from="95" to="95">Toxicophobia (being poisoned)</choice>
			<choice from="96" to="96">Triskaidekaphobia (the number 13)</choice>
			<choice from="97" to="97">Tropophobia (moving or making changes)</choice>
			<choice from="98" to="98">Xenoglossophobia (foreign languages)</choice>
			<choice from="99" to="99">Xenophobia (strangers or the unknown)</choice>
			<choice from="100" to="100">Zoophobia (animals)</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="prime_motivations">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Personal Egotism</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Personal Honor</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Love of Duty</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Pleasure/Excitement</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Knowledge</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Love</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Power</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Wealth</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Social Status</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Vengeance</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="quirks">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Pious</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Absent Minded</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Religious</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Eccentric</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Clever</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Impatient</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Irreverent</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Non-Conformist</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Insomniac</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Artist</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">Generous</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Collector</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">Liar</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">Intolerant</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">Loquacious</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">Altruist</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">Seducer</choice>
			<choice from="18" to="18">Gambler</choice>
			<choice from="19" to="19">Passionate</choice>
			<choice from="20" to="20">Brutal</choice>
			<choice from="21" to="21">Spendthrift</choice>
			<choice from="22" to="22">Rebellious</choice>
			<choice from="23" to="23">Cunning</choice>
			<choice from="24" to="24">Phobic</choice>
			<choice from="25" to="25">Careless</choice>
			<choice from="26" to="26">Sedate</choice>
			<choice from="27" to="27">Obsessive</choice>
			<choice from="28" to="28">Truthful</choice>
			<choice from="29" to="29">Pacifist</choice>
			<choice from="30" to="30">Hypochondriac</choice>
			<choice from="31" to="31">Precise</choice>
			<choice from="32" to="32">Loyal</choice>
			<choice from="33" to="33">Musical</choice>
			<choice from="34" to="34">Alcoholic</choice>
			<choice from="35" to="35">Childish</choice>
			<choice from="36" to="36">Conservative</choice>
			<choice from="37" to="37">Miserly</choice>
			<choice from="38" to="38">Poet</choice>
			<choice from="39" to="39">Cynical</choice>
			<choice from="40" to="40">Paranoid</choice>
			<choice from="41" to="41">Radical</choice>
			<choice from="42" to="42">Compulsive</choice>
			<choice from="43" to="43">Honorable</choice>
			<choice from="44" to="44">Stubborn</choice>
			<choice from="45" to="45">Disorder</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="valued_people">
			<choice from="1" to="1">I like almost everyone</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">I hate almost everyone</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Every person is a valuable individual</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">People are obstacles to be destroyed if they cross me</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">People are untrustworthy. Don't depend on anyone</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">People are wonderful</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">I love everyone!</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">I'm neutral to most people.</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">No one can hurt me!</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Yeah, Whatever...</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">No one ever understands me...</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">You're born, you live, you die</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">People must earn my respect! No free rides here</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">People are tools. Use them, and then discard them</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">People are sheep, born to be led</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">People are scum and should all be killed</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="valued_person">
			<choice from="1" to="1">A parent</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Brother or sister</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Lover</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Friend</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Yourself</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">A pet</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Teacher or mentor</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Public figure</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">A personal hero</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">No one</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">You value everyone!</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">Everyone you know is a valuable person</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">You don't even value yourself...</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">You dislike everyone, even yourself</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">You hate everyone and everything</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="valued_posession">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Beautiful memories</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">family heirloom</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">momento</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">picture</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">valuable collectable</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">vehicle</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Money and wealth</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">weapon</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">tool</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">piece of clothing</choice>
			<choice from="11" to="11">photograph</choice>
			<choice from="12" to="12">book or diary</choice>
			<choice from="13" to="13">recording</choice>
			<choice from="14" to="14">musical instrument</choice>
			<choice from="15" to="15">piece of jewelry</choice>
			<choice from="16" to="16">toy</choice>
			<choice from="17" to="17">letter</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="4A">
			<choice from="1" to="1">YOU GET LUCKY</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">DISASTER STRIKES</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="4B">
			<choice from="1" to="1">you made a friend.</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">you made an enemy.</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="disaster_reaction">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Clear your name</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Live it down and try to forget it.</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Hunt down those responsible and make them pay!</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Get what's rightfully yours</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Save, if possible, anyone else involved in the situation.</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="disaster_strikes">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Financial Loss or Debt</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Imprisonment</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Illness or addiction</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Betrayal</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Accident</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Lover, friend or relative killed</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">False Accusation</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Hunted by the Law</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Hunted by a Neo-Corp</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Mental or Physical Incapacitation</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="enemy_cause">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Caused the other to lose face or status</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Caused the loss of a lover, friend or relative</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Caused a major humiliation</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Accused the other of cowardice or some other personal flaw</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Caused a physical disability</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Deserted or betrayed the other</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Turned down other's offer of job or romantic involvement</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">You just didn't like each other</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Was a romantic rival</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Foiled a plan of the other's</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="enemy_do">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Go into a murderous, killing rage and rip his face off!</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Avoid the scum</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Backstab him indirectly</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Ignore the scum</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Rip into him verbally</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="enemy_hate">
			<choice from="1" to="1">They hate you</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">You hate them</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">The feeling's mutual</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="enemy_resources">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Just themselves</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Themselves and a few friends</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">An entire Gang</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">A small Corp or Local Altcult</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">A large Corp or entire Enclave</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">An entire Altcult</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="enemy_who">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Ex friend</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Ex lover</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Relative</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Childhood enemy</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Person working for you.</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Person you work for</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Partner or co-worker</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Boostergang member</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Neo-Corporate Exec</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Government Official or Altcult Leader</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="event_menu">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Big Problems, Big Wins</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Friends &amp; Enemies</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Romantic Involvement</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Nothing Happened That Year</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="friend_relationships">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Like a big brother/sister to you</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Like a kid sister/brother to you</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">A teacher or mentor</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">A partner or co-worker</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">An old lover (choose which one)</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">An old enemy (choose which one)</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Like a foster parent to you</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">A relative</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Reconnect with an old childhood friend</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Met through a common interest</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="love_complicated">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Someone got preg and now you have a kid</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Your old lover just secretly showed up</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Their old Lover just secretly showed up</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">One of you had a kid in the past and they just showed up</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">You have a terrible secret you&#8217;re hiding from them</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">An old enemy of yours just showed up</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">An old enemy of theirs just showed up</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="love_events">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Happy love affair</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Tragic love affair</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Love Affair with problems</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Fast Affairs and Hot Dates</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Life got complicated</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="love_mutual">
			<choice from="1" to="1">They still love you</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">You still love them</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">You still love each other</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">You hate them</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">They hate you</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">You hate each other</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">You're friends</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">No feeling's either way; it's over</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">You like them, they hate you</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">They like you, you hate them</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="love_problems">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Your lover's friends/family hate you</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Your lover's friends/family would use any means to get rid of you</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Your friends/family hate your lover</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">One of you has a romantic rival</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">You are separated in some way</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">You fight constantly</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">You're professional rivals</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">One of you is insanely jealous</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">One of you is "messing around</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">You have conflicting backgrounds and families</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="love_tragic">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Lover died in accident</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Lover mysteriously vanished</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">It didn't work out</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">A personal goal or vendetta came between you</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Lover kidnapped</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Lover went insane</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Lover committed suicide</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Lover killed in a fight</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Rival cut you out of the action</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Lover imprisoned or exile</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="lucky_table">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Make a Powerful Connection in Local Government</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">Financial Windfall</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">Big Score on job or deal</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">Find a Sensei</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">Find a Teacher</choice>
			<choice from="6" to="6">Powerful Altcult member owes you one favor</choice>
			<choice from="7" to="7">Local Nomad Pack befriends you</choice>
			<choice from="8" to="8">Make a Friend in a local Altcult</choice>
			<choice from="9" to="9">Local Boostergang likes you</choice>
			<choice from="10" to="10">Find a Combat Teacher</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="powerful_connection">
			<choice from="1" to="1"> It's in a local Security Force.</choice>
            <choice from="2" to="2"> It's in a local Altcult Leader's Office.</choice>
            <choice from="3" to="3"> It's in the City Mgr's Office.</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="betrayel_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1"> you are being blackmailed.</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2"> your secret was exposed</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3"> you were betrayed by a close friend in either romance or career (you choose).</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="accident_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1"> you were terribly maimed and must subtract -2 from your DEX.</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2"> you were hospitalized for x months that year.</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3"> you have lost x months of memory of that year.</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4"> you constantly relive nightmares of the accident and wake up screaming.</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="death_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1"> They died accidentally.</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2"> They were murdered by unknown parties.</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3"> They were murdered and you know who did it. You just need the proof.</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="accusation_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1">The accusation is theft</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">The accusation is cowardice</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">The accusation is murder</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">The accusation is rape</choice>
			<choice from="5" to="5">The accusation is lying or betrayel</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="crime_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1">Only a couple local renta-cops want you</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">It's an entire local Security force</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">It's an Altcult Militia</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">It's the FBI or equivalent national police force</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="corporation_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1">It's a small, local firm</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">It's a larger corp with offices Citywide</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">It's a big, national corp with agents in most major cities</choice>
			<choice from="4" to="4">It's a huge multinational megacorp with armies, ninja and spies everywhere</choice>
		</table>
		<table name="breakdown_type">
			<choice from="1" to="1">It is some type of nervous disorder, probably from a bioplague- lose 1 pt. REF</choice>
			<choice from="2" to="2">It is some kind of mental problem; you suffer anxiety attacks and phobias. Lose 1 pt from your PRE Stat</choice>
			<choice from="3" to="3">It is a major psychosis. You hear voices, are violent, irrational, depressive. Lose 1 pt from your PRE, 1 from REF</choice>
		</table>
	</tables>
</preferences>